<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/lopez/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Is an oligolopostic banking system more resilient and at what cost? A study of the competitiveness of the Canadian banking structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Giesinger</surname></persName>
							<email>michael.giesinger@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">EVP &amp; CRO, Canadian Western Bank, Canada</note>
								<orgName type="institution">EVP &amp; CRO</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Canadian Western Bank</addrLine>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">10303 Jasper Avenue, Edmonton, AB T5J 3X6, Canada</note>
								<address>
									<addrLine>10303 Jasper Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>T5J 3X6</postCode>
									<settlement>Edmonton</settlement>
									<region>AB</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">Director, Risk, Investment Management Corporation of Ontario, Canada</note>
								<orgName type="department">Director, Risk, Investment Management Corporation of Ontario</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">200 King Street West, Suite 2300, Toronto, ON M5H 3T4, Canada</note>
								<address>
									<addrLine>200 King Street West, Suite 2300</addrLine>
									<postCode>M5H 3T4</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>ON</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Is an oligolopostic banking system more resilient and at what cost? A study of the competitiveness of the Canadian banking structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Received (in revised form): 15th July, 2020</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2020-11-01T14:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>bank policy making</term>
					<term>systemic risk management</term>
					<term>efficient markets</term>
					<term>competitive market</term>
					<term>system efficiency</term>
					<term>system utility</term>
					<term>financial system stability</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Services group, designing and implementing risk-management solutions globally. Bogie has authored and coauthored three books and numerous papers, as well as contributing to various books on risk management. Currently, he focuses on optimisation of capital and business mix management and strategic risk management.</p><p>Suite 3000,</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>The financial sector is a key part of the Canadian economy. It provides 7 per cent of the Canadian gross domestic product (gross value added by industry) compared with 11 per cent in the United Kingdom and 7.5 per cent in the United States. Large banks, with access to capital markets and other resources, are an essential part of the economy. They provide employment (280,000 bank employees and C$26.5bn in salaries and benefits according to the Canadian Bankers Association), financing to 1 million small and medium enterprises/small business entities, pay C$7.3bn in taxes, and pay C$16bn in dividend income. These statistics highlight the merit of asking whether the financial sector is operating in the best interests of all stakeholders.</p><p>The Canadian banking industry is concentrated in six systemically important banks 1 controlling more than 90 per cent of the market in Canada. There are a few small banks. The difference in size between the smaller and bigger banks is vast: the combined value of Canadian Western Bank (CWB) and Laurentian Bank is just over C$4.7bn, or a quarter of the size of the National Bank of Canada, the smallest of the Big Six. Put another way, Royal Bank of Canada's (RBC's) trading activities alone drive more revenue than Laurentian's and CWB's entire banking activities combined, and RBC's annual asset growth is roughly the size of Laurentian and CWB put together. Canadian domestic systemically important banks (D-SIBs) are subject to a capital surcharge, enhanced supervision, recovery and resolution planning, and increased disclosure. These requirements are generally consistent with the global systemically important banks (G-SIB) framework to which RBC and Toronto Dominion Bank (TD) are also subjected.</p><p>The Canadian banking system, like its Australian counterpart, is often credited for being resilient. Its oligopolistic structure and rent costs are viewed as necessary for the resiliency of the system. In this paper, the authors ask a series of questions: Was the system resilient and, if yes, how was it achieved? Is bigger better, and what is the trade-off between the size advantages, such as increasing diversification benefits and economies of scale, and the systemic risk the size creates? What is the cost of the oligopolistic structure, and is it possible to increase competitiveness in the system, thus reducing the oligopolistic rent without sacrificing the resiliency?</p><p>These topics have been increasingly the concern of policy makers, particularly improving competitiveness without sacrificing the resiliency. The Competition Bureau of Canada states that:</p><p>The pendulum has begun to swing back toward an approach to financial policymaking that considers competition as important as other policy objectives such as safety and stability. A number of reports by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), for example, contributed to a growing concern for competition in the financial sector. These reports highlight the importance of competition to enhance the effectiveness of the financial system, which, in turn, allows for long-term economic growth.</p><p>The World Bank also suggests that the importance of competition 'should not be sacrificed for the sake of stability.' 2 A recent study by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) <ref type="bibr">3</ref> states that stability and competition can (and should) coexist.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Defining the Ideal Structure for the Canadian Financial Sector</head><p>In a 2017 consultative paper, <ref type="bibr">4</ref> the Department of Finance defines the criteria to assess whether Canada's financial sector is functioning effectively as given subsequently:</p><p>1. Stability: The sector is safe, sound, and resilient in the face of stress. 2. Efficiency: The sector provides competitively priced products and services and passes efficiency gains to customers, accommodates innovation, and effectively contributes to economic growth. 3. Utility: The sector meets the financial needs of an array of consumers, including businesses, individuals, and families, and the interests of consumers are protected.</p><p>The subsequently given direct quotes from the same consultative paper illustrate the desire to increase competition and properly calibrate with risk:</p><p>. . . Canadians benefit through greater access, choice, and competition from the presence of new market entrants and a framework that encourages innovation in financial services. Small and mid-size banks are also important contributors to competition and innovation. In the nearterm, refining a smooth entry and exit process will contribute to a dynamic and contestable marketplace.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Streamlining the Bank Entry and Exit Framework Ease of entry and orderly exit are key features of a dynamic and contestable financial services marketplace. Ease of entry allows financial sector entrepreneurs, including FinTechs, to enter the financial sector efficiently to target underserved niches and offer new products and services to Canadians.</head><p>Orderly exit allows firms to voluntarily leave the sector smoothly should their business plans change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Positioning a Competitive and Innovative Sector to Support Long-Term Economic Growth</head><p>Competition in the financial sector can be a tool to promote long-term economic growth. A competitive sector can deliver more affordable and innovative financial services to consumers and can provide credit to dynamic, cutting-edge areas of the economy. The level of competition in the sector needs to be carefully calibrated against a well-managed regulatory and legislative framework for oversight and risk. Over the longer term, the Department will consider the current balance of economic growth and risk management and whether refinements are needed to better position the sector to be competitive and innovative . . .</p><p>. . . Small and mid-sized banks can contribute to longterm economic growth, as they often target different areas and market segments, such as small businesses. Over the last few decades, the Government has undertaken a number of legislative reforms to promote the entry of small and midsized banks. Bank ownership rules have been broadened to allow small and mid-sized banks to be owned by foreign banks, non-bank financial institutions, and commercial firms.</p><p>The Government will continue to apply proportionality in the development of policy and regulation going forward. However, despite this approach, small and mid-sized banks note that they face challenges due to proportionately higher regulatory burden and capital expectations relative to their larger counterparts, and are of the view that these requirements are not reflective of the overall stability risk posed by small and mid-sized banks.</p><p>With this context in mind, the Department will analyze the contribution that small and mid-sized banks can make to increasing capital formation and efficient credit allocation, which are important financial functions that can grow the Canadian economy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Defining an Oligopolistic Market Structure</head><p>For this paper, the authors adopt a common definition of oligopolistic market structure as one in which there is a small number of firms, typically in an industry with significant barriers to entry with limited product differentiation, and in which the sellers set prices. In a mature oligopolistic market structure, the firms recognise each other's interdependence in their pricing and output policies. Dick 5 elaborated on the oligopolistic market structure in the context of global banking and defined it as an 'asymmetric oligopoly', in which there is a small set of dominant banks that operate as an oligopoly coexisting alongside a number of significantly smaller fringe banks, which typically do not have pricing power except in small local or fringe markets. Dick 6 extends this analysis to suggest that an asymmetric oligopoly will exist regardless of the market size and has impact on the quality of product offering by large banks vs fringe banks. The authors also adopt the term 'oligopolistic rent' to refer to the excess income received by the owners of oligopolistic firms in excess of the owners' opportunity cost.</p><p>Finally, a competitive marketplace is defined by the Competition Bureau of Canada as: 7</p><p>In a competitive marketplace, companies use different approaches to maximize their profits. Some reduce prices, while others exploit more efficient means of production to increase margins and reduce costs. Others gain market share through innovation, offering consumers differentiated products and services that deliver more value than those of their competitors. When companies attempt to increase profits by raising prices, they risk losing customers to their competition or attracting new competitors who see the opportunity for profitable market entry. In markets that lack competition or where the threat of competitive entry is low, firms can maximize profits by increasing prices, without the same risk of losing customers. In these markets, the competitive drive to innovate, improve quality or become more efficient in production is largely lost. Consumers ultimately pay higher prices without a commensurate improvement in value.. . . Such uncompetitive outcomes are more likely when a market is characterized by a high concentration of suppliers, high barriers to entry and high costs of switching for customers.</p><p>There are a few key elements that create an environment in which competition can flourish: low barriers to entry; low costs of switching for customers; complete and accurate information; and a sufficient number of effective competitors. Without these elements, markets are likely to tend away from competitive outcomes.</p><p>A more competitive marketplace increases the efficiency of the financial system in terms of lower prices and increased choice in products and services (as well as more value for money) for the users of banking products and services. This is the definition of oligopolistic market structure, competitive marketplace and efficiency that the authors will use in this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IS BIGGER BETTER? SHAREHOLDERS' PERSPECTIVE: ABSOLUTE VS SYSTEMIC SIZE</head><p>Are large banks better for shareholders, customers and taxpayers? Demirguc-Kunt and Huizinga 8 make an important distinction between 'absolute size' and 'systemic size' for banks. They measure a bank's 'absolute size' by its total assets (measured by the logarithm of banks' assets), and its 'systemic size' by its size relative to the national economy (measured by the ratio of the bank's liabilities to the home country's GDP). They conclude that large absolute size can be desirable, while large systemic size ie when total assets exceeds 18.7 per cent of home country GDP, is never desirable.</p><p>The authors 8 have also found that increasing in absolute size (without becoming systemically large) presents banks with a trade-off between risk and return: banks of large absolute size tend to be more profitable, as indicated by the return on assets, but they also possess a higher bank risk, as measured by a (lower) z-score. 9 The z-score is the probability of bank insolvency, calculated as 'the sum of the mean return on assets and the mean ratio of equity to assets, divided by the standard deviation of the return on assets'. Conversely, they found that systemically large size is 'an unmitigated bad, reducing return on assets without reducing the risk'. In other words, systemically large banks are less profitable without clear evidence of lower risk. The researchers 8 suggest that these banks may have run out of profitable business opportunities in their domestic markets.</p><p>This study suggests that absolute and systemic size affect shareholder return positively and negatively, respectively. Therefore, the size of the home country's economy is an important factor. The optimal bank size (as determined by a tradeoff between risk and return) declines with the size of the home country's economy; banks located in larger countries may have a larger optimal size and can increase their absolute size with a relatively small negative impact on systemic size.</p><p>A practical example may be D-SIBs and G-SIBs operating in smaller countries such as in Canada, Australia and smaller European countries attempting to compete with US banks. They are systemically important, but their home economies were not sufficiently large or complex to generate the kinds of returns required for them to operate as a trading/ investment bank; fee/trading activities require global scale, which is difficult to achieve when the home economy is small.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Benchmarking Canadian Banks</head><p>This study begs the question: are Canadian banks absolutely large or systemically large? Demirgüç-Kunt and Huizinga 8 use a large sample group of almost 14,000 banks to estimate the sample mean of the ratio of total liabilities to home country GDP (liabilities-to-GDP) equal to 0.046. Most banks are shown to be small relative to GDP ie 86.9 per cent of banks have liabilities over GDP of less than 0.05. Many banks are, however, much larger relative to GDP. About 8.2 per cent of banks have liabilities that exceed 10 per cent of GDP and 1.0 per cent of banks have total liabilities exceeding GDP. The summary statistics are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> and the distribution of liabilities to GDP ratio by bin is provided in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.  Demirguc-Kunt and Huizinga 8 provide parameter estimates, which imply that assets growth causes an increase in return on asset until a bank's assets-to-GDP ratio reaches 0.187 and liabilities-to-GDP ratio reaches 0.167 (assuming an average liability-to-asset ratio of 0.892). This means that asset growth would improve the return on assets for most banks in the global sample.</p><p>The given figures suggest that most banks globally may be operating in a competitive environment. The authors find that this is not the case for the large Canadian banks. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows the total assets and log total assets for the eight largest Canadian banks, which are used to determine the absolute size of each bank, and the ratio of liabilities-to-GDP and assetsto-GDP, which are used to determine the relative systemic size of each bank. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> highlights the extremely large size of RBC and TD compared to the other Canadian banks, as well as the size of the five largest banks next to the smaller regional banks.</p><p>Using the reference liabilities-to-GDP level of 0.167 from Demirguc-Kunt and Huizinga (2011) as the optimal systemic size, one can see that Canada's five largest banks have exceeded this point. TD and RBC are significantly higher than the optimal size (not surprisingly they are both G-SIBs). For context, TD is about 40 per cent of the size of JPMorgan, the largest US bank, but the Canadian economy is roughly 9 per cent of the US economy. Therefore, TD is about four times the relative size of the largest US bank. Similarly, the concentration of the top five banks is also much higher in Canada. The fifth largest US bank is 4.6 per cent of the US economy, while the fifth largest Canadian bank, CIBC, is 24. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Differences between institutional efficiency and systemic efficiency</head><p>Allen et al. 10 compare the efficiency of large Canadian banks with US commercial banks and derive two noteworthy conclusions:</p><p>-Based on the efficiency metrics selected, Canadian banks are as efficient as US banks. -Canadian banks can become more efficient by becoming bigger.</p><p>The study was undertaken before the 2007-08 financial crisis, and therefore predates a widespread understanding of both the systemic risk posed by institutions that are 'too-big-to-fail' and the costs of that risk. The study also predates the rise of FinTech, which is a game-changer in terms of the economies of scale required. The critical mass (size) the banks needed in the past (which likely led to oligopolistic structures in many countries) is not necessarily a good indicator of their optimal size going forwards, considering the efficiency gains FinTech can provide. Most importantly, Allen et al. define efficiency in terms of the efficiency of the banks themselves, and not in terms of the efficiency of the financial system, as described by the Competition Bureau of Canada. These two are not interchangeable in an oligopolistic marketplace. While the focus of this paper is the resiliency of the system, and the systemic risk, the topic can only be meaningfully discussed in the context of stability and the utility counterparts. The analysis given earlier suggests that Canadian banks are systemically large; it does not, however, describe the impact of this systemic growth on shareholders, customers and taxpayers. The subsequent analysis more fully examines the impact of having an oligopolistic market structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>What are the Costs and Benefits of an Oligopolistic Structure? Potential Benefits of an Oligopolistic Structure</head><p>The following are possible hypotheses that support an oligopolistic structure in Canadian banking: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Potential Costs of an Oligopolistic Structure</head><p>In contrast with the earlier-mentioned facts, the following counter-hypothesises oppose an oligopolistic structure:</p><p>1. Stability: A system consisting of a few large banks could be less stable due to the systemic risk it creates. In an oligopolistic structure, the cost of systemic risk (regulatory compliance costs and D-SIB capital surcharges) can be passed on to the end users by means of higher prices for services and products, which may also diminish the efficiency of the system. D-SIBs, by definition, pose systemic risk. Given this elevated systemic risk and the risk of being 'too big to fail', it may be that the risk is shifted towards taxpayers and customers, who have no influence over management's risk taking, representing a value transfer from taxpayers and customers to and shareholders of these banks.</p><p>The Canadian regulatory framework has multiple tools to help mitigate the systemic risk that the D-SIBs pose, such as more intensive supervision, additional bail-in capital requirements, recovery and resolution planning requirements, enhanced disclosure requirements and the higher capital requirements for D-SIBs and G-SIBs. These mitigants are effectively a systemic risk insurance to protect the system, which naturally has a cost. For example, bail-in debt is estimated to be 50bps higher than otherwise equivalent debt. Higher capital requirement has also a significant cost. Formally, D-SIBs are required to hold 100 bps more capital than their non-D-SIB counterparts. The actual difference is larger. When one compares the common equity tier (CET) 1 ratios of Canadian D-SIBs and small banks, one observes that D-SIBs hold about 2 per cent more CET 1 ratio, which translates to 22 per cent more capital for D-SIBs (assuming 9 per cent CET 1 for small banks and 11 per cent for D-SIBs). This means, all else being equal, a systemically important bank must charge 22 per cent more for its products and services to have the same returns on equity (ROE) as a bank that is not systemically important.</p><p>In short, an oligopolistic structure creates systemic risk, the cost of which is borne by the users of financial services, which further diminishes the efficiency of the financial system. This systemic risk and the resulting capital charge can surpass the capital efficiency created by the diversification benefit of the D-SIBs' larger portfolios.</p><p>Lastly, it may not actually be easier to regulate a few large banks, considering the difficulty in overseeing the D-SIBs' complex operations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Efficiency and Utility:</head><p>2.1 An oligopolistic structure may result in higher prices for the end customers in Canada due to oligopolistic rent, and decreased efficiency due to lack of competition. Large banks may be inefficient despite their economies of scale due to their oligopolistic power, which allows them to pass costs onto their clients rather than having to internally manage costs effectively. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANALYSIS OF EVIDENCE</head><p>The trade-off between increasing diversification benefits and systemic risk with increasing bank size <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> provides a stylised illustration of the trade-off between diversification benefits and systemic risk as bank size increases. Diversification benefit can increase at a decreasing rate as the bank grows, whereas systemic risk increases at an increasing rate. There exists a point where the increased systemic risk outweighs the diversification benefit (Point A in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). Moreover, the maximum net benefit is achieved at a bank size that is materially below Point A. (Point B in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). In other words, a smaller bank can capture significant diversification benefits by increasing its size without creating significant systemic risk.</p><p>The big five Canadian banks (all D-SIBs and G-SIBs) are already systemically large. They are much larger than their US counterparties relative to the size of their economy. It is reasonable to argue that as they grow, the increase in their systemic risk will outweigh the diversification benefits created. This means that the 'sweet spot' (Point B) where the net benefit is maximised is only available for today's smaller banks or to new entrants. As new entrants and smaller banks grow, they can create diversification benefits without materially increasing systemic risk. They should also be able to remain relatively specialised in certain segments, services, and asset classes where they have a competitive advantage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evidence of Oligopolistic Rent; Measuring Market Concentration and Market Power</head><p>Market power is often measured by examining the premium charged over the price per unit of goods and services, and by the ability to alter goods and services to enhance profitability and maintain this high level of profitability even in the event of major shocks. The relationship between market structure, performance, and market power exercised by firms can also be indicative of competition. This paper considers measures of performance relevant to the financial system, such as margins, return on equity, operating costs and expenses in undertaking an assessment of competition. The other key questions • consumers' ability to apply competitive pressure on financial system providers;</p><p>• firms' ability to maintain persistently high market shares and profit levels, even under stress;</p><p>• the existence of impediments to the growth of smaller firms and new entry;</p><p>• material information asymmetry between consumers and providers;</p><p>• evidence of an inability or unwillingness by consumers' to switch products or providers; and</p><p>• the level innovation and efficiencies as a result of rivalry.</p><p>A contestable market is one where the credible threat of new entrants exerts discipline over incumbent providers in their market behaviour. Where there is a credible threat of entry or expansion, incumbents know that if they earn profits in excess of a fair compensation for risk, or are slow to respond to the changing needs and preferences of consumers by developing new products or new business methods, they could lose market share (and future profits) to rivals. Barriers to entry and expansion tend to weaken, and in the extreme may eliminate this threat reducing the pressure on incumbents to constantly strive to improve their offer. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> The authors now present the evidence they were able to gather. The evidence supports the following, with analysis to follow: 1) Canadian banks were able to alter product and service offerings to maximise their profitability. 2) Canadian banks maintained high profitability both through the crisis and afterwards. 3) Canadian banks were able to maintain declining expense ratios through the crisis and afterwards. 4) Canadian banks were able to concentrate their product offering on profitable segments at the expense of innovation.</p><p>These findings are evidence of market power, which is an indication of a lack of competition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>In their oligopolistic structure, do Canadian banks pass efficiencies onto their customers?</head><p>It is evident that Canadian banks weathered the 2007/8 crisis significantly better than their international counterparts. They did not require an explicit bailout from the government, and they maintained their profitability and ROEs at higher levels than their international counterparts. Given subsequently in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> are the comparisons of their ROEs with those of their counterparts. The stability of the Canadian banks' ROE, with no government bailout, is used as evidence of the soundness of the Canadian financial system. While the observation itself is true, how this happened and whether it was desirable deserve further discussion. The evidence indicates that Canadian banks were able to quickly pass on costs of the crisis to customers rather than reducing costs through slower, but more effective cost management. A useful comparison is the trend in expense ratios (noninterest expense to net operating revenue) between US and Canadian banks, as seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>.</p><p>The average expense ratio for a sample of systematically important US banks from 2007 to 2016 increased from 59 per cent to above 72 per cent in the years after the crisis. This was followed by cost control and efforts to increase revenue, resulting in a decline to 63 per cent within five years. For Canada, the expense ratio declined from the early 2000s through the crisis to a low in 2017. This suggests that Canadian banks were able to either rapidly adjust to the new cost environment and maintain revenues at precrisis levels or pass elevated costs onto customers. The Committee on the Global Financial System 15 includes average cost-to-income ratios for major economies of which only three developed economies -Canada, Sweden and Australia -show a significant declining trend, which continues through the crisis. U-din, Tripe and Kabir 16 demonstrated that Canadian banks posted better efficiency scores than their US peers following the crisis, which they proposed was driven by more market power in the Canadian banking sector, and a higher concentration. This suggests that rather than efficiency gains being passed to customers, it is customers who absorb the immediate costs of crisis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Does oligopolistic scale in Canada improve international competitiveness?</head><p>Large Canadian Banks' returns on equity (ROE) in Canada (for their Canadian operations) are between 15-20 per cent. The foreign operations of these same banks (the largest five with significant US presence) combined make a passable ROE of about 10 per cent according to The Economist, 17 which is very much in line with other major US banks. The environment in the United States cannot sustain an ROE of over 10 per cent at this time. The Canadian banks' ROA for their US operations is, however, low (in the case of TD and BMO, very low) relative to the other banks operating in the United States, as seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. The evidence suggests that US entities are subsidised by their Canadian counterparties and the benefit of international expansion to create shareholder value is questionable. The Canadian D-SIBs' US presence adds cross-country diversification to their portfolios. This is, however, not expected to be large for two reasons:</p><p>1. The US and Canadian economies are highly correlated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Regulatory divergence between Canada and</head><p>the United States, as well as the solo capital requirements, reduces the fungibility of capital between the United States and Canada, thus reducing the effective recognition of the diversification benefits between the D-SIBs' US and Canadian businesses.</p><p>These observations on profitability beg the question: why are the Canadian subsidiaries of Canadian banks so much more profitable than their US subsidiaries in the United States? This may be partly explained by the fact that the US market is much more competitive. The examination of the profitability post crisis is also telling. In either case, oligopolistic scale in Canada does not necessarily translate into global, or even international, competitiveness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Does an oligopolistic structure promote innovation?</head><p>The Canadian banks demonstrated an ability to alter their product and service offerings to maximise profitability. Following the 2007/8 crisis, the large Canadian banks narrowed their product service offerings with an eye to maintaining profitability. This is likely a response to wherever the new rules made these services less profitable, banks exited and/or narrowed products and services accordingly to maintain a high level of profitability. The same ability is also observed after moving from Basel I to Basel II. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref>, we see Canadian large banks' asset mix before and after Basel II.</p><p>Capital requirement for lending activities is a very important driver of probability. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref>, one can see that the banks were able to alter their credit portfolios very significantly; they increased the credit that became more profitable under the Basel II rules, and vice versa. Therefore, it is the capital requirement that determines what services and products are offered in what capacity. This is not a typical competitive system, where consumer needs drive product and service offerings. This is a strong indication of a supply-driven market eg an oligopoly, which reduces system utility. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> It has been observed that D-SIBs control the downstream and upstream supply chain in capital markets where the effective competition may also be hindered. Over the past two decades, Canadian banks have become more dependent on residential mortgage lending. At the same time, they have reduced their income from noninterest income-generating activities, which offer product diversification, at the cost of potentially higher income volatility. This gives the appearance of less risk with more stable income and lower risk-weighted assets (RWAs) but introduces </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implications of Oligopolistic Structure on Customers</head><p>Demirguc-Kunt and Huizinga 20 confirm that, among other things, banks in countries with a more competitive banking sector have smaller margins and are typically less profitable. They highlight that effective banking regulation requires balancing of stability and efficiency. Interest margins are a useful indicator of the balance of those two components: if interest margins are too high, it suggests the environment favours stability at the cost of efficiency, and the opposite if interest margins are too low.</p><p>There is limited research which analyses the impact of market concentration, in the context of Canadian banking, on interest rates charged to customers. One would, however, expect, as with any highly concentrated industry, that strong market power would result in higher margins for banks. Beyhaghi, D'Souza and Roberts <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">21</ref> demonstrate that Canadian banks enjoy a funding advantage for both deposits and subordinated debt. While deposit holders have limited alternatives, debt-holders respond to bank-specific risk factors, a behaviour that implies a reduced risk premium for Canadian banks. Most importantly, they demonstrate that the largest six Canadian banks enjoy a funding advantage over their domestic peers -even during the crisis period. This is consistent with other analysis, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">22</ref> which confirms that larger banks typically charge lower deposit rates than smaller banks. In a competitive market, positive economic profit is supposed to erode over time, especially following major events such as the 2007/8 crisis. This did not happen for Canadian banks; therefore, arguably there was an 'implicit bailout' for the benefit of bank shareholders in Canada, whose cost was not borne by the taxpayers (as in the case of an explicit bailout) but was borne by the end users of the banking services and products.</p><p>The aim of sound policymaking cannot be to foster a financial system where banks are 'too big to fail' at the expense of their clients and for the benefit of their shareholders. As a matter of fact, in a competitive market, firms do and should fail due to the competitive forces. The reason that bank failure is avoided is the systemic size of these banks, which is in itself an indication of a noncompetitive market. It is, then, a self-fulfilling prophecy that a system creates systemically large banks and then tries to avoid their failure; their so-called strength and resilience are then attributed to the strength of the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>WHY IS COMPETITION NOT IMPROVING DESPITE ITS BENEFITS?</head><p>To understand why competition does not increase although it yields favourable systemic benefits, one needs to understand the barriers to growth for the smaller banks which are brief ly discussed subsequently. They are classified into four categories: (i) market structure, (ii) government policy, (iii) regulatory structure and (iv) the regulatory capital regime.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>i) Barriers imposed by the current market structure</head><p>• D-SIBs' market power: D-SIBs can pass cost increases to their clients and set prices with lower consequences for their market share. Smaller banks are price takers and do not challenge the major banks' market power.</p><p>• Brand recognition and first-mover advantage:</p><p>Large banks have both first-mover advantage, better brand recognition and more effective means of gaining exposure to new customers due to their marketing and sponsorship programmes.</p><p>• Distribution network: The retail branch network of D-SIBs would be expensive for new entrants to establish and maintain. FinTech (and the virtual branch) has the potential to be a game changer.</p><p>• Better and cheaper access to capital for large banks.</p><p>• Cost of innovation and cost of keeping up with technology.</p><p>• Access to funding: The majority of bank funding comes from deposits. For example, these deposits represent approximately 59 per cent of total authorised deposit-taking institution (ADI) funding in early 2018, in Australia. New entrants and smaller banks have reduced access to retail demand deposits due to a smaller branch network and reduced access to more expensive broker/agent Guaranteed Investment Certificate (GIC) market, which is largely controlled by D-SIBs. Their ability to attract more deposits is limited by (i) market dominance by major banks, (ii) limited customer switching and (iii) flight to safety in a crisis given 'too big to fail' implicit government guarantee. Smaller institutions are not only affected by their lower credit ratings; they also often pay the major banks to arrange and manage their debt and other issuance, as the major banks have the required skills available in-house. The cost of these services raises the overall cost of funds for smaller institutions.</p><p>• Higher operating costs: Due to lack of scale, smaller banks have higher processing and operating costs per dollar of assets forcing them to operate in riskier or niche markets where unit returns are higher. To reduce their operation costs and combat the inadequacy of their distribution channels, they also buy loans from brokers as opposed to originating them themselves, which increases operational risk (as seen in the Home Capital example).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ii) Barriers imposed by government policy</head><p>Government business activities that compete with private provision, whether for-profit or not-for-profit, should comply with competitive neutrality principles to ensure they do not enjoy a net competitive advantage simply as a result of government ownership. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">23</ref> The government prudential framework and supervisory activities should endeavour to maintain 'competitive neutrality' by minimising unnecessary or artificial regulatory distinctions among different entities undertaking different activities which exhibit similar risk profiles. The later mentioned asymmetrical government subsidies violate the competitive neutrality principle. The Deposit Guarantees provided to credit unions and the government-owned ATB Financial are not available for smaller banks that directly compete with ATB and the credit unions. ATB's cost of capital is often assumed to be government borrowing rate, although taxpayers as the 'owners' should require a much higher rate. ATB maintains an efficiency ratio that publicly traded banks cannot afford. D-SIBs and G-SIBs benefit from implicit government guarantees. Their 'too big to fail' status creates an expectation of government intervention if one or more of these banks were in financial difficulty. This status lowers the cost of funds for these banks. The 'too big to fail' perception affects the cost of wholesale funding as well. Credit rating agencies and investors see these institutions as safer due to the prospect of government support, and therefore ascribe higher credit rating to them and, in turn, lend money at lower rates or on less strict terms. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The Bank of Canada does offer Emergency Lending Assistance, which is available for smaller banks as well, but interestingly, this assistance is available under 'idiosyncratic' liquidity shock as opposed to the systemic liquidity shock that would impact D-SIBs and G-SIBs.</p><p>This implicit guarantee increases D-SIBs' profitability by lowering their funding cost. Therefore, it is effectively a value transfer from taxpayers to the D-SIBs' shareholders. The Australia Prudential Regulatory Authority <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">24</ref> notes the moral hazard associated with implicit guarantees derived from the perceived expectation of government support, which can encourage (systemically important financial institutions) to take excessive risks, reduce market discipline and create competitive distortions, further increasing the probability of distress in the future. As a result, the direct cost of support associated with moral hazard is borne by taxpayers, representing a large and unacceptable implicit public subsidy of private enterprise. iii) Barriers imposed by the regulatory structure</p><p>• A two-tier regulatory approach provides no clear guidelines for the smaller banks trying to grow materially and compete effectively with D-SIBs. Under the proportionality principle, D-SIBs are subject to full-scale regulation whereas there is an effort to reduce the compliance and regulation cost for smaller banks which do not pose systemic risk. The regulations are, however, still largely undefined for the smaller players who are trying to make the transition to become a larger bank. In this context, the regulatory objective appears to be reducing the burden on the small banks provided they stay in the 'small bank box' by the proportionality principle, as opposed to making the 'transitioning rules' proportional.</p><p>• D-SIBs are incentivised to buy out fast-growing new up-and-comers. A D-SIB can apply the advanced internal rating-based (AIRB) licence to the portfolios of the standardised banks, thereby generating immediate capital savings. These capital savings would create a significant buyout premium, considering limited costs to absorb new portfolios. iv) Barriers imposed by the regulatory capital regime Banks need to hold capital to protect their creditors and depositors for the risk they are taking. The amount of this capital is one of the most, if not the most, important driver of a bank's profitability. To illustrate the point, a 20 per cent reduction (increase) in capital would change a 10 per cent ROE to 12.5 per cent (8.3 per cent ). In Canada, the six large banks are under the AIRB Capital regime, which is risk sensitive whereas the smaller banks are under the Standardized Capital Regime, which is typically more punitive and risk insensitive. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 6</ref>, the authors provide two examples of risk weight (RW) calculations for large corporate loans and mortgages under the AIRB and the Standardized approaches. The authors have a rating system with 19 distinct risk ratings (RR), where RR1 (lowest risk) has a probability of default (PD) of 5 bps, while RR19</p><p>(highest risk) has a PD of 30 per cent. With risksensitive AIRB, the capital charge is proportional to PD (and LGD); for a given LGD, RR1 has the lowest capital charge or RW, whereas RR19 has the highest capital charge or RW. In this example, for the corporate loans, the RW increases from 20 per cent for RR 1 to 230 per cent for RR 19; whereas, with the Standardised approach, the RW is constant at 100 per cent regardless of the risk rating. This example demonstrates that Standardized Capital is much more punitive than AIRB capital between RR1 (AAA/AA) to RR10 (BB), and vice versa between RR11 (BB-) to RR19 (C).</p><p>The risk-insensitive nature of Standardized Capital makes it very difficult for a Standardised bank to compete with AIRB banks for investment-grade corporate loans. As an example, for an AAA/AAgrade loan, Standardised banks need to hold five times more capital than AIRB banks holding the exact same loan. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref>, the authors quantify this in terms of ROE. The ROE under AIRB is stable between RR1 (AAA/AA) and RR16 (CCC). This is not surprising as with increased risk, risk-sensitive AIRB capital increases, but so does the price for the loan. The details are provided in Appendix 1. A Standardised bank, on the other hand, cannot produce a reasonable ROE up to RR8 (BBB-) or even RR9 (BB+) when considering the higher funding cost. Note that a Standardised bank produces a very high ROE where the risk-insensitive capital falls short of the risk taken (RR14 (B-) and 16 (CCC)).</p><p>The same principle holds true for mortgages. As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 8</ref>, under the risk-sensitive AIRB, RW changes from 1.5 per cent for RR 1 to over 60 per cent for RR 19, whereas it is constant at 35 per cent under the Standardised approach. For an RR1 A-mortgage, a Standardised bank would have to hold 23 times more capital than an AIRB bank; therefore, smaller banks cannot compete with AIRB banks for highly-quality A-mortgages. It is estimated that, on average, AIRB banks hold 6 per cent RW for all residential A-mortgages and 11 per cent RW for uninsured A-mortgages, compared to 35 per cent for the Standardised banks. It is not surprising to see Standardised banks and mortgage monoliners specialising in the Alt-A mortgages where not only is the pricing higher, but the Standardised capital falls below the risk-sensitive AIRB capital.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 9</ref>, the authors quantify the implication of this effect in terms of ROE. Under AIRB, A-mortgages produce strong ROEs between RR 1 and 6, while Standardised banks can produce very strong ROEs between RR 5 and 15 for A-mortgages. Details are provided in Appendix 2.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>POTENTIAL SOLUTIONS</head><p>In this paper, the authors make the case that competition, stability, efficiency and utility can coexist and are indeed complementary. This is because increasing competition by enabling the smaller banks to grow reduces the systemic risk as well as the undesired implicit public subsidy of private enterprise. While reducing the barriers to increase competition is a large topic in itself, the authors provide a quick look at some of the potential solutions in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Regulatory mandate to improve competitiveness</head><p>When one examines the Office of the Superintendent of Financial Institutions' (OSFI's) mandate, one observes that it does not include explicit requirements for promoting competitiveness. Some may argue this is appropriate, as OSFI should focus solely on the safety and soundness of the Canadian financial system. But even if this were the case, there is a common ground between the two concerns -soundness and competitiveness -and an opportunity to achieve both objectives.</p><p>Enabling growth for smaller banks helps reduce the overall risk of the system in two ways: 1) Smaller banks can improve access to the financial system and increase their scale to improve diversification benefits without creating systemic risk; and 2) Without an A-IRB license, smaller banks will neither be able to diversify sufficiently nor get out of the high-risk segments that they are forced to occupy today under the Standardised capital regime.</p><p>Encouraging smaller banks to improve ROEs by increasing revenues and lowering capital requirements, typically through moving to A-IRB capital charges, will increase efficiency in the system and help reduce the risk. It has been observed that OSFI is beginning to work with smaller banks more closely to establish a new process, more appropriate   Any regulatory process should only impose the minimum burden to achieve A-IRB accreditation. Recognising this, the APRA (Australian Prudential Regulation Authority) has announced changes to its IRB accreditation process to make it easier for authorised deposit-taking institutions to achieve accreditation without weakening the overall standards that accreditation requires. These changes include a staged accreditation process and de-linking of the previous eligibility of having advanced modelling to determine the capital held against both credit and operational risk. Since the rule change, a number of banks have started the process, and one has already earned IRB accreditation.</p><p>The Bank of England's Prudential Regulation Authority <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">25</ref> has issued clarifying statements to their guidance on IRB modelling requirements which moved to make it easier for smaller banks to become IRB accredited. Its approach has focused on an initial agreement between the regulator and the applicant, setting clear expectations with regard to the requirements for accreditation and how banks can use external data when they do not have sufficient data of their own for IRB modelling. 3. Help protect access to liquidity for smaller players, in particular for the broker/agent GIC market.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Unintended</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consequences of the Government Policy</head><p>Remove the asymmetry in subsidies. Consider extending the deposit guarantee subsidy to the smaller banks. for the smaller banks, to earn their A-IRB licences. A-IRB models are very valuable risk-management tools. Regulators would naturally expect these tools to be utilised to their full capacity within a well-developed risk function (rather than simply as capital calculators). Therefore, A-IRB not only appropriately connects risk-taking to capital, but also significantly improves smaller banks' riskmanagement capabilities. Swapping excess, risk insensitive capital with risk sensitive capital and improved risk management is a trade-off the regulator should always favour.</p><p>There is also another, more fundamental, issue: 'too big to fail'. In a competitive market, firms should fail, as seen in the UK and US markets. OSFI's mandate is to prevent bank failures under the assumption that a strong regulator will ensure a strong system. Bank failures, however, are necessary for a competitive market to ensure that risks are priced correctly, and rewards allocated to the correct stakeholders. Ideally, systemic risk must be managed so that bank failures can be tolerated, with the aim of promoting competitiveness in the financial system.</p><p>As a larger policy issue, competition and stability can and must coexist. For example, the study by the Australian Financial System, Productivity Commission states the following:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competition can support stability, for example, through preventing excessive concentration in the financial system that would otherwise lead to dependency on a very small number of providers. Anti-competitive behaviour does nothing for system stability and can potentially undermine it. A financial system that contains only one or two large dominant providers (that are too big to fail and hence implicitly underwritten by the relevant government) could be very stable at least in the short term. However, such providers would have strong incentives to engage in adverse behaviour, knowing that any upside would be captured by shareholders while losses would be protected by government intervention or could be readily recovered by exercise of market power. Competition can and should reduce the reliance of the financial system on any single provider and thus is itself a method to reduce the incentives for excessive risk taking by financial providers.</head><p>Competition can also deliver more consumer-oriented products and lower interest rates in the economy, reducing the risk of borrower default. The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) noted that there is an important role for government to safeguard the stability of the banking system. However, competition policy should not be viewed as a threat to this objective. Indeed, increased competition in concentrated retail banking markets could help make those markets more robust and effective over time, and less prone to poor performance and failure . . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) 2017)</head><p>On the other hand, regulators can fear that strong competition could erode standards of prudent conduct and lead banks to take more risks in lending activity in order to maintain their profitability. The fear of unfettered competition can be exaggerated. We cannot simply always prefer stability, without acknowledging a significant cost to economic activity from such a default position.</p><p>If every regulatory decision must have the same objective -always adding to an institution being unquestionably strong -innovations in risk management will be ignored heaping cost on to consumers.</p><p>The Commission's view is that competition and stability in the financial system can coexist; but such a coexistence is unlikely at the extremes of market structures.</p><p>Key highlights and main conclusions with selected quotes from the study are provided in Appendix 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>COVID CRISIS AND FUTURE RESEARCH</head><p>The concern over the economic cliff effect from the COVID epidemic is growing. There will be a critical regulatory response. A misguided desire for resiliency will favour (perhaps an even increasingly) concentrated Canadian financial system, where the desire to increase competition may take a back seat yet again. This perceived resiliency of the oligopolistic system effectively is the banks' marketing power to pass on the cost of the crisis and the following regulations to the end users of their products and services, and what is discussed in this paper with respect to the 2007/8 crisis is likely to reoccur. This will be a very interesting future area of research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSIONS</head><p>The Canadian banking industry is concentrated in six systemically important banks, together controlling more than 90 per cent of the market in Canada. Demirgüç-Kunt and Huizinga 8 make an important distinction between 'absolute size' and 'systemic size' for banks. They measure a bank's 'absolute size' by its total assets, and its 'systemic size' by its size relative to the national economy. They conclude that large absolute size can be desirable, while large systemic size is not. In other words, growth can be beneficial as long as the bank in question does not reach large systemic size. Canadian banks' systemic size is much larger than that of their US counterparts. The largest Canadian bank by assets is roughly four times the relative size of the largest US bank by assets.</p><p>There are potential benefits to an oligopolistic market structure. An oligopolistic structure may allow banks to use scale to create stable, resilient financial sectors, to create efficiencies which they can pass on to customers, to compete internationally to improve returns for shareholders, and to create or import innovation from outside the country. Evidence suggests that the Canadian financial sector is not providing these benefits.</p><p>Canadian banks have struggled to use their scale in Canada to create value for shareholders by expanding internationally. This is partially explained by challenges of expanding into more competitive markets. Finally, there is evidence that Canadian banks have used their scale to concentrate on more profitable segments in response to regulatory changes and financial stress rather than enhancing their product offering through innovation. This is not a typical competitive system where consumer needs drive product and service offerings; rather, the supply chain drives these offerings in reaction to the capital regime. This is a strong indication of a supply-driven market eg oligopolistic, which reduces system utility.</p><p>These examinations suggest the existence of an oligopolistic rent, as evidenced by Canadian operations being so much more profitable due to higher prices for products and services in Canada than their US operations. This rent is supported pass on the cost of the crisis and the following regulations to the end users of their products and services of their products and services, and their ability to alter products and services to maximise profitability. In a competitive market, positive economic profit is supposed to erode over time, especially following major events such as the 2007/8 crisis. This did not happen for Canadian banks; therefore, arguably there was an 'implicit bailout' in Canada whose cost was not borne by the taxpayers (as in the case of an explicit bailout) but by the end users of the banking services and products (the payers of the oligopolistic rent). The aim of the policymaking cannot be to foster a financial system where banks are 'too strong to fail' at the expense of their clients. As a matter of fact, in a competitive market, firms do and should fail due to the competitive forces. The reason that bank failure is prevented by governments is the systemic size of these banks, which in itself is an indication of a noncompetitive market. It is then a self-fulfilling prophecy that a system creates systemically large banks, and then tries to avoid their failure. Their strength and resilience are then attributed to the strength of the system.</p><p>An oligopolistic structure also creates systemic risk. The requirement for elevated capital buffers for D-SIBs and G-SIBs suggests that regulators are aware of the higher systemic risk posed by large banks. The authors theorised the diversification benefit vs systemic risk trade-off with an increasing bank size. The diversification benefit can increase but at a decreasing rate as the bank grows, whereas systemic risk increases at an increasing rate. There exists a point where the systemic risk outweighs the diversification benefit as the bank continues to grow. The big six Canadian banks are already systemically large (D-SIB or G-SIB), and, as a matter of fact, their size relative to the home economy is much larger than their US counterparts. Therefore, it is reasonable to argue that as they grow further, the increase in their systemic risk outweighs the diversification benefits created. Thus, the 'sweet spot' where the net benefit is maximised is now available for today's smaller banks. As these banks increase their asset size and grow, they can create diversification benefits without creating systemic risk at the same rate.</p><p>If a more competitive system is desired for both stability and efficiency of the system, the authors brief ly examined why this is not happening and the gap between smaller banks and the big banks continues to widen. This is because there are formidable barriers for smaller banks to grow and become more competitive. Among barriers, the two-tier regulatory capital system is particularly important. The Standardized Capital Regime that smaller banks are under is punitive and not risksensitive. This eliminates smaller banks' access to certain markets, forces them to stay and compete in certain high-risk segments, and significantly reduces their chances to diversify. The authors provide examples of markets where smaller banks, under the Standardized Capital Regime, cannot compete with the large banks which have very significant capital advantage under the A-IRB. The inability of the smaller banks to compete in these markets diminishes the utility and the efficiency of the financial system, as those services are predominantly provided by the generalist D-SIBs and G-SIBs at a higher cost.</p><p>The authors' objective here is not to debate the optimal size for the big Canadian banks, but to question whether large banks are better for their stakeholders. The evidence presented makes a strong case that the next tide of growth should come from the smaller banks, not from Canadian D-SIBs and G-SIBs growing even bigger. Over the past decade, D-SIBs and G-SIBs continued to grow, increasing the gap between their size and that of smaller banks. This trend indicates that there are strong barriers to growth for smaller banks, preventing them from being able to catch up to their larger peers.</p><p>Competition, stability, efficiency and utility can coexist, as a matter of fact, they can be complementary. This is because increasing competition by enabling the smaller banks to grow reduces the systemic risk as well as the undesired implicit public subsidy of private enterprise. PD: probability of default, LGD: loss given default, EL: expected loss, ROE: return on equity, ALT-A: alternative A-paper, RR: risk rating, IRB: internal ratings based approach. RWA: risk weighted assets</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>APPENDIX 3: A COMPARISON OF CANADIAN AND AUSTRALIAN BANKING SYSTEMS</head><p>The Canadian and Australian financial systems are considered to be very similar; they are both dominated by a few large banks which are highly profitable and resilient, as proven during the 2017-18 financial crisis. A very comprehensive study was undertaken by the Australian Productivity Commission (Productivity Commission 2018) and the main conclusions of that study bear a remarkable resemblance to those discussed in this paper from stability, efficiency and utility perspectives. A major conclusion is that 'Competition can support stability'. Key highlights and main conclusions with selected quotes from the study are provided subsequently.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1.</head><p>The system structure is also oligopolistic.</p><p>¡ Australia's banking sector is an established oligopoly. Australia, with an oligopolistic banking system, is not at either extreme and so can (and should) seek to give genuine attention to both competition and stability. 2. The large banks possess large market power and the level of competition is poor, which effectively reduces the utility and efficiency of the financial system. ¡ There is evidence that the high concentration of market power among a very small number of institutions is resulting in poor consumer outcomes in Australia. Households and businesses may be paying, through unnecessary fees and low-value products, for a system that is exposed to use of entrenched market power. ¡ The four major banks as a group hold substantial market power, as a result of their size, strong brands and broad geographical reach. This is substantially supported by regulatory settings, which contribute to the major banks' structural advantages. As a result, the major banks have the ability to pass on cost increases and set prices that maintain high levels of profitability -with minimal loss of market share. Being a systemically important institution with assured funding in times of crisis, and protection from takeover, gives a consequent embedded ability to set prices to recover additional regulatory costs. ¡ The smaller banks and nonbank financial institutions typically follow the pricing trend set by the major banks, and are not a significant competitive constraint on the major banks' market power. ¡ This approach is unlikely to result in prices that are reflective of the cost incurred by the most efficient institution; at best, it will result in prices that reflect the costs of the least efficient major bank (or in some markets, the higher marginal cost of smaller, competitive fringe institutions). For competition analysis, it is significant that the market is in a state that persistently allows this. ¡ The major banks, the dominant force in the market, are able to charge higher premiums above their marginal costs, compared with other institutions. Approximately half of the average loan price that major banks charge is estimated to be a premium over the marginal cost -double the margin that other Australian-owned banks have and well above that of banks in other high income countries. ¡ On the other hand, the Commission has not found evidence of a pass through of cost efficiencies to consumers. Achieving ROE targets is an important factor in major banks' interest rates decisions, and one that has tended to lead to higher rates charged to existing borrowers, rather than aggressive discounting intended to expand market shares. ¡ The major banks' market power has allowed them to set interest rates to borrowers and depositors that enable them to remain highly profitable -without significant loss of market share. 'This has continued to occur even in the face of market shocks (such as the global financial crisis) and notable regulatory changes that have increased their costs and would otherwise have eroded the return on equity.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'The consistently high returns of Australia's largest financial institutions are over and above those of many other sectors in the economy and in excess of banks in most other developed countries post GFC. In recent times, regulatory changes have put pressure on bank funding costs, but by passing on cost increases to borrowers, Australia's large banks in particular have been able to maintain consistently high returns on equity (ROEs).' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Banks and insurers alike almost invariably argue that price shifts are tied to a shift in costs. But the ability across a sub-set of firms in a market to maintain prices and profitability in all market conditions (changes in not just industry-wide costs but also business-specific cost changes) is a very clear sign of market power.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'What allows market power to be sustained in Australia's financial system is a combination of features evident in the way providers, consumers and regulators operate: ¡ Market power as a result of established presence; ¡ Market power as a result of regulatory arrangements; ¡ Market power as a result of funding advantage and operational efficiency; ¡ Market power reinforced by integration ¡ Market power reinforced by consumer inertia' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'A highly profitable financial system is not a bad thing. Consistently strong and profitable institutions can be beneficial for consumer and investor confidence, which, in turn, lowers the cost of funds and return required on investment. But if the market were workably competitive, keeping prices high in order to deliver profits would cause a significant number of consumers to switch and encourage a lower price provider, with profits shifting along with shareholder expectations. It is, at least in part, the stickiness of consumers with their current bank, insurer or adviser that allows these providers to maintain profits without loss of market share.' (Productivity Commission 2018) 3. For smaller banks, there are formidable barriers to growing and competing in this market, the elimination of which is necessary for increasing competition. These barriers include:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Additional capital they need to hold:</head><p>¡ 'Risk weights are a cornerstone of prudential standards, as they determine the amount of regulatory capital that a bank must hold against each loan it makes. These risk weights are used by all ADIs other than the major banks, which use internal risk-based (IRB) models approved by APRA. The comparatively higher risk weights mean that most lenders are generally required to hold more regulatory capital than are lenders using IRB models.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'In contrast to the standardised approach, the IRB approach to regulatory capital holdings (used by only the very largest banks in Australia) allows banks to take into account various indicators and a range of pledged security, including residential mortgages, in calculating the risk weights applying to SME lending. As a result, those ADIs using the IRB approach are able to apply risk weightings to more fully reflect the risk of the loan than under the standardised approach. The average risk weighting used by ADIs under the IRB approach was around 48 per cent for loans below C$1m (which can be considered as retail exposure) and 55 per cent for loans of more than C$1m compared to 100 per cent under the standardised approach for SME lending not secured by a residential mortgage. As with residential mortgages, the difference between weightings used through the more refined IRB approach and the standardised approach for SME lending provide an advantage in funding costs to those banks using the IRB method rather than the standardised weightings.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'The cost of funds accordingly affects institutions' ability to compete in the market for lending; those that face lower costs of funds are in a better position to either attract more customers by charging less for credit, or increase their profits. Banks that invest in an internal risk management model approved by APRA -primarily the largest banks -gain a cost advantage in terms of the capital held against loans made. The Commission estimates that the collective cost saving for the four major banks from using their own risk models is well in excess of AUD$1bn a year.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Institutions that have not invested in development of these risk models must follow APRA's standardised risk weights. APRA's approach to risk weights has increased the cost disadvantage for smaller institutions and reduced the scope for price competition, potentially harming consumers. As a consequence, for an SME loan that is not secured by a residence, Australia's smaller banks need to hold up to twice as much capital as the major banks -in effect, paying up to twice as much to be able to offer loans to their customers. This provides Australia's larger banks with an advantage in SME lending and skews competitive opportunity away from consumer interests.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'From a prudential perspective, changing weights to more closely reflect the inherent risk of different types of loans would help prevent excessive provisioning of regulatory capital for low-risk assets and under-provisioning for riskier assets. Thus, it would contribute to a more efficient banking system. From a competition perspective, reducing the gap between IRB and non-IRB banks, as well as help achieve better competitive outcomes through lower costs for safer, low LVR loans.' (Productivity Commission 2018)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Less available and higher cost of funds:</head><p>The larger banks not only control most of the deposit base, but their implicit bailout status as D-SIBs (thus the government guarantee) reduces their cost of funding.</p><p>(This paper argues that this is effectively a value transfer from the taxpayers to the shareholders of these banks.) ¡ 'Larger banks benefit from lower costs of funding, compared with smaller institutions. Size, scope and incumbency have enabled them to increase their share of the deposit market, retain better access to offshore funding markets and raise funds at relatively cheaper rates due to their higher credit ratings, which in part reflect an expectation of government support.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'By incorporating perceived government support in their relative ratings of Australia's banks, rating agencies further embed the major banks' "too big to fail" status.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'It is just not credible for a government or regulator to promise not to step in and prevent large-scale bank failure in a financial crisis. The public know they will, and no amount of words will dispel this expectation.' (Productivity Commission 2018) 14 ¡ 'The "too big to fail" perception affects the cost of wholesale funding -as credit ratings agencies and investors see such institutions as safer due to the prospect of government support, and therefore ascribe higher credit ratings to them and, in turn, lend them money at lower rates or on less strict terms.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Smaller institutions are not only affected by their lower credit ratings; they also often pay the major banks to arrange and manage their debt and other issuance, as the major banks have the required skills available in-house. The cost of these services raises the overall cost of funds for smaller institutions.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Overall, there is a distinct difference in the cost of funds faced by larger and smaller players. Major banks are generally able to set the price on deposits, and they benefit from higher credit ratings, which lower the cost of their funds raised in wholesale funding markets. Even when funding costs decline, major banks' market power allows them to decide whether they pass on the savings to their borrowers.' (Productivity Commission 2018)</p><p>The barriers to growth, as mentioned earlier, handcuff small-and medium-sized banks and prevent them from providing effect competition. The FinTech space does not look promising either.</p><p>¡ 'For now, neither foreign entrants nor fintechs appear to pose a substantial threat to major banks' dominant positions: more entrants alone are not a panacea to drive sustained competition across Australia's financial system.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Fintechs are not, on present indications, likely to have the kind of competitive disruptive effect that would alter the market power of major banks in the foreseeable future.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'In the long term, lowering barriers to entry and growth, including greater access to consumer data, may lead fintechs to favour competition against incumbents over collaboration.' (Productivity Commission 2018)</p><p>4. Increasing competition in the system must be an explicit objective. This requires regulatory intervention in order to enforce competitive neutrality by actively seeking to minimise unnecessary or artificial regulatory distinctions between different entities undertaking activities with similar risk profiles. But this cannot be achieved under the current regulatory structure. ¡ 'Competition and stability must coexist.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Regulation is present in all markets and need not undermine workable competition.</p><p>In contrast, competition is poor in many of the financial markets we have examined.' (Productivity Commission 2018)</p><p>¡ 'The financial system is a vital part of the Australian economy because of its size and the key role it plays in enabling and supporting transactions by individuals, households, businesses and government.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Effective competition in the financial system should drive innovation in product offerings, improvements in product quality and variety, greater efficiency and lower prices, for the benefit of business and consumers.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'The financial system should be stable. But equally, it should ensure that those for whom it exists -the businesses investing in the Australian economy and the individuals whose consumption drives the majority of economic activity -receive good service at transparent prices, and can have confidence that unquestionably strong institutions are not simply exploiting the market power they might have.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Given the size and importance of Australia's financial system, and the increasing emphasis on stability since the global financial crisis, the lack of an advocate for competition when financial system regulatory interventions are being determined is a mistake that should now be corrected.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'In Australia . . . while there is much handwringing about competition, there has been little shift in the regulatory culture. The emphasis on stability -best represented by the repeated use of the phrase "unquestionably strong" -persists.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'An important step towards addressing this imbalance is for regulators themselves to recognise better the effects that their actions may have on competition, and take steps to minimise them where closer study may show that scope exists to do so.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'A competition champion must be appointed among the financial regulators who shape policy. The purpose of this change is to create an opportunity to stress test the competitive implications of an intervention before it is made.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Adding cost to the larger banks without altering their market power does not lift competition, harms consumers and is counterproductive. Policy measures aimed at addressing either conflicts of interest or regulatory interventions that disregard competition can mitigate adverse outcomes for consumers even if the current industry structure remains largely intact.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Cost interventions (such as changes to risk weights) have been presented as targeting both stability and competition. While such interventions may have achieved stability objectives, they have had adverse consequences for competition. Interventions that raise the cost of funds for larger institutions to offset their cost advantages do not improve competition and will harm consumers' (Productivity Commission 2018) (as they pass the cost to their clients). ¡ 'We must look further afield for substantial offsets to current market power.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Competition can support stability, checking irresponsible behaviour of providers and improving outcomes for consumers, and must be allowed to flourish.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'The Commission supports APRA's efforts to decrease accreditation burdens.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'APRA could allow partial accreditations for portfolio or risk type (for example, credit)</p><p>depending upon where models are easily separable without compromise. Though prudential regulators would prefer a full IRB accreditation, accrediting some functions of an ADI would be preferable to no risk modelling whatsoever and importantly, allow more banks to achieve lower costs for their major lending portfolios.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Cost advantage is one source of the major banks' market power, and it can be tempting to respond crudely to that by lifting costs for them. But as we have shown in other chapters, where there is no change to the market power of the affected institutions, this does not benefit consumers nor the economy. It merely lifts costs. It is unfortunately easier for policymakers to add cost to the major banks than it is to guide regulators towards minimising the effects on competition, or avoid unintended opportunities to exploit re-pricing.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Changing the way the financial regulators interact to address competition is highly desirable -given the market power of financial market participants, full analysis of the effect of regulators' actions on competition is critical.' (Productivity Commission 2018) ¡ 'Weighing up competition and stability requires financial regulators to conduct comprehensive analysis of potential material competitive effects of prudential measures. However, there is no agency that currently has this as a primary task.' (Productivity Commission 2018)</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Distribution of the liabilities-to-gross domestic product (GDP) ratioNote: This figure shows the percentages of banks with a liabilities-to-GDP ratio in successive bins of size 0.05. The banks with a liabilities-to-GDP ratio larger than 1 are represented in the bin on the right.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5 per cent of the Canadian economy, a difference of 530 per cent. The top five Canadian banks represent a total of 200 per cent of Canadian GDP, while the top five US banks only represent 48 per cent of the US economy.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Diversification benefit vs systemic risk with respect to increasing portfolio size</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: ROE in Canada and the United States</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Expense ratio in Canada and the United States</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>According to McKeown 18 in 2006, residential and mortgages represented 21 per cent of total assets for Canadian banks, broadly stable compared with 20 per cent of total assets in 1997. Following the crisis, in 2015, mortgages represented 28 per cent of total assets, an increase of 30 per cent. The contrast is even starker when compared in absolute terms: mortgages increased from C$228bn in 1997 to C$457bn in 2006, roughly doubling in nine years, and then up to C$1.3 trillion in 2015, an increase of 180 per cent over the same time horizon through the crisis.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Distribution of bank credit before and after Basel II (Credit to Individuals vs Business and Government) *Source: Angus Watt Advisory Group, National Bank Financial Wealth Management</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: RW comparison for large corporate loans Note: RWA, risk-weighted assets</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: ROE comparison under standardised and AIRB capital charge for corporate loans Note: ROE, returns on equity</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: RW comparison for mortgages Note: RWA, risk-weighted assets</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: ROE comparison for mortgages Note: ROE, Returns on equity</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary statistics from Demirguc-Kunt and Huizinga 8</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Variable Observations</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Standard Deviation</cell><cell>Min.</cell><cell>Max.</cell></row><row><cell>Assets</cell><cell>13,834</cell><cell>21.766</cell><cell>2.096</cell><cell>14.947</cell><cell>28.550</cell></row><row><cell>Liabilities over GDP</cell><cell>13,805</cell><cell>0.046</cell><cell>0.221</cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>4</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Canadian banks -absolute and systemic size metrics</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>National</cell><cell>CIBC</cell><cell>BNS</cell><cell>RBC</cell><cell>TD</cell><cell>Laurentian</cell><cell>CWB</cell><cell>BMO</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Bank</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Bank</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Assets in USD Constant Dollars</cell><cell cols="6">$138,053 $317,443 $514,003 $681,119 $718,264 $26,216</cell><cell cols="2">$14,852 $398,489</cell></row><row><cell>($M)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Log assets</cell><cell>25.7</cell><cell>26.5</cell><cell>27.0</cell><cell>27.2</cell><cell>27.3</cell><cell>24.0</cell><cell>23.4</cell><cell>26.7</cell></row><row><cell>Relative Size (Liabilities/GDP)</cell><cell>0.107</cell><cell>0.245</cell><cell>0.392</cell><cell>0.522</cell><cell>0.552</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.011</cell><cell>0.305</cell></row><row><cell>Relative Size (Assets/GDP)</cell><cell>0.113</cell><cell>0.259</cell><cell>0.420</cell><cell>0.556</cell><cell>0.587</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>0.012</cell><cell>0.326</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>players in the United States and such a dichotomy is inherently difficult to maintain. 2.3 An oligopolistic bank will serve more profitable markets and can underserve the less profitable ones or abandon them during downturns; thus, an oligopolistic structure does not maximise utility. Both De Haas et al. 11 and Morgan, Pinkovskiy, and Yang 12</figDesc><table><row><cell>demonstrate that recent trends in banking</cell></row><row><cell>have resulted in banks closing branches in</cell></row><row><cell>sparsely populated areas, while retaining</cell></row><row><cell>and opening new ones in economically</cell></row><row><cell>stronger population centres, resulting in</cell></row><row><cell>oversaturation of some neighbourhoods</cell></row><row><cell>2.2 D-SIBs' international businesses may be</cell></row><row><cell>costing their shareholders and Canadian</cell></row><row><cell>stakeholders. Large Canadian banks may not</cell></row><row><cell>be internationally sufficiently competitive</cell></row><row><cell>in their foreign operations, and their</cell></row><row><cell>Canadian businesses may be 'subsidizing'</cell></row><row><cell>their international business. D-SIBs can</cell></row><row><cell>also pass their international regulatory/</cell></row><row><cell>compliance costs (eg heavy and very costly</cell></row><row><cell>US compliance requirements) to their</cell></row><row><cell>Canadian clients, given their oligopolistic</cell></row><row><cell>power in Canada. Therefore, Canadians</cell></row><row><cell>may also be subsidising foreign compliance</cell></row><row><cell>cost. Canadian bank's US strategy is an</cell></row><row><cell>interesting topic of discussion, as it shows</cell></row><row><cell>the disadvantages of being systematically</cell></row><row><cell>large and therefore exhausting the growth</cell></row><row><cell>potential within their home country while</cell></row><row><cell>simultaneously not being large enough to</cell></row><row><cell>compete internationally. Most D-SIBs have</cell></row><row><cell>expanded outside of Canada to diversify</cell></row><row><cell>their sources of income and limited growth</cell></row><row><cell>opportunities in Canada. After many years,</cell></row><row><cell>it is still unclear whether this strategy has</cell></row><row><cell>rewarded shareholders given the Canadian</cell></row><row><cell>banks' low ROA in their US businesses.</cell></row></table><note>While the US market is certainly attractive, the competition is intense. Canadian banks, with oligopoly power at home, are forced to be niche and the formation of 'banking deserts', those areas in which there are no bank branches within a 10-mile radius of the census tracts' centre. Franke and Dahl 13 show that potential banking deserts are typically served only by small banks. This suggests that G-SIBs and D-SIBs, which have been reducing their branch network (US banks reduced the total branch network by roughly 5 per cent between 2009 and 2014) to focus on more profitable regions, have left the smaller banks as the only remaining point of access to financial services in many potential deserts. 2.4 An oligopolistic structure and government policy may be creating barriers to entry and to growth for smaller banks, although greater participation by small banks would increase market efficiency. The oligopolistic barriers to entry, referred to in the financial industry as the 'moat', is a function of regulatory carrying costs, the large infrastructure, systems and human capital expenditure to build and grow a financial institution, and is also by driven by customer preference for institutions, which have a demonstrated performance history. The size of a D-SIB creates economies of scale thereby lowering the costs and increasing efficiency. To prove this, one needs to examine if the larger banks are more cost efficient relative to their smaller counterparts and, if true, whether the efficiency gains are passed onto their customers.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Relative ROA rankings of the Canadian banks' US subsidiaries</figDesc><table><row><cell>FY2017 Data, Source: FFEIC</cell><cell>TD</cell><cell>RBC</cell><cell>BMO</cell><cell>CIBC</cell><cell>All CDN</cell><cell>&gt;C$3bn</cell><cell>All US</cell></row><row><cell>CDR UBPR Returns</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Banks</cell><cell>Assets</cell><cell>Banks</cell></row><row><cell>ROA</cell><cell>0.58%</cell><cell>0.85%</cell><cell>0.43%</cell><cell>0.94%</cell><cell>0.56%</cell><cell>0.99%</cell><cell>0.98%</cell></row><row><cell>Relative Ranking (&gt;$3bn in Assets)</cell><cell>261/302</cell><cell>204/302</cell><cell>273/302</cell><cell>165/302</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Relative Ranking (All US Banks) 4206 / 5719 3004 / 5719 4652 / 5719 2552 / 5719</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Potential solutions to make the Canadian financial market more competitive Arguably, it is not the government's place to interfere but let the market factors play out Support development of the small banks and FinTechs. FinTechs can create virtual branches, breaking the barriers to growth created by the large banks' branch network. They also drastically reduce operational costs, thereby eliminating the need for economies of scale as a barrier to growth.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Factor Restricting</cell><cell>Potential Solution</cell></row><row><cell>Competition</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Market Factors</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Barriers imposed by an</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Oligopolistic Market</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Structure</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Barriers Resulting from the Regulatory Structure</cell><cell>1. Fast-track developing a regulatory regime for FinTechs. 2. Remove glass ceiling for small-and medium-sized banks by making transitioning rules and the cost of transition to a larger bank proportional to the size and complexity of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>the organisation. In particular, make the A-IRB license 'earnable' by smaller banks.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Regulatory motivation for an easier A-IRB accreditation has already gained momentum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>internationally.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>government guarantees, which would boost the smaller banks' debt ratings reducing their wholesale funding cost. Extend subsidies to support innovation especially by smaller players. Further improve resolutions for a costless, frictionless exit. Make buyouts of smaller FIs more difficult.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Consider new subsidies for smaller banks and FinTechs similar to those provided to small</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">businesses, eg:</cell></row><row><cell>•</cell><cell>Tax breaks,</cell></row><row><cell>•</cell><cell>Deposit guarantees,</cell></row><row><cell>•</cell><cell>Credit given to investments in infrastructure projects (eg AIRB, new banking systems</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>etc) by means of, for example, temporary additions to capital adequacy ratios</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(currently they are deducted from Tier 1 calculations), and</cell></row><row><cell>•</cell><cell>Other forms of</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Federal Reserve Bank of New York, available at: https://libertystreeteconomics.newyorkfed. org/2016/03/banking-deserts-branch-closingsand-soft-information.html (accessed 14th</figDesc><table><row><cell>November, 2018). 13 Dahl, D.and Franke, M. (2017) '"Banking deserts" become a concern as branches dry up', The Regional Economist, The Federal Reserve Bank of St Louis, Vol. 25, No. 2, available at: https://www.stlouisfed.org/publications/ regional-economist/second-quarter-2017/ banking-deserts-become-a-concern-as-branches-dry-up (accessed 23rd October, 2018). 14 Commission AGP (2018) 'Competition in the Australian financial system', Report No 89. 15 System CotGF (2018) 'Structural changes in banking after the crisis', CGFS Papers 60, available at: https://www.bis.org/publ/cgfs60. htm (accessed 25th October, 2018). 16 U-Din, S., Tripe, D. and Kabir, M. H. (2018) 'Market power and efficiency in banking: The case of USA and Canada', SSRN Electronic Journal, available at: https://ssrn.com/ abstract=3118703 (accessed August 11th, 2018). 17 The Economist (2017) 'Canadian banks don't face a crisis. They do face a strategic trilemma', The Economist, London. 18 McKeown, R. (2017) 'An overview of the Canadian banking system: 1996 to 2015', Working Paper 1379, Economics Department, Queen's University. 19 This is consistent with the ACCC's finding for the Australian market which states that Prompted in part by regulatory change, the composition of banks' lending portfolios has shifted. Over time, housing lending has become the key component of ADIs' credit activities, at the expense of business lending. This ref lects APPENDIX 1 Risk Ratings RR1 RR2 RR3 RR4 RR5 RR6 RR7 RR8 RR9 RR10 RR11 RR12 RR13 RR14 RR15 RR16 RR17 RR18 RR19 AAA/AA+ AA/AA-A+ A A-BBB+ BBB BBB-BB+ BB BB-B+ B B-CCC+ CCC CCC-CC C PD 0.05% 0.07% 0.11% 0.16% 0.21% 0.28% 0.43% 0.65% 1% 1.40% 2% 3% 4% 6% 8% 11% 15% 21% 30% RWA IRB LGD = 40% 19% 23% 30% 37% 42% 49% 61% 74% 87% 97% 108% 121% 132% 150% 167% 188% 209% 227% 234% RWA Standardised 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% 100% Rate 1.65% 1.75% 2.00% 2.05% 2.15% 2.25% 2.40% 2.75% 3% 4.00% 4% 5% 5% 6% 8% 10% 10% 10% 11% ROE IRB LGD = 40% 15% 15% 18% 15% 15% 14% 12% 13% 15% 18% 16% 14% 13% 13% 17% 17% 10% 2% -9% ROE Standardised 3% 3% 5% 6% 6% 7% 8% 10% 13% 18% 18% 16% 17% 19% 29% 31% 20% 5% -21% APPENDIX 2 Risk Rating PD RWA IRB LGD=10% RWA Standardised EL Capital IRB LGD=10% ROE Standardised, -3% -3% -1% -1% 0% 1% 1% 4% 7% 11% 12% 10% 11% 13% 23% 25% 14% -2% -27% Capital Standardised Higher funding cost RR1 RR2 RR3 RR4 RR5 RR6 RR7 RR8 RR9 RR10 RR11 RR12 RR13 RR14 RR15 RR16 RR17 RR18 RR19 0.05% 0.07% 0.11% 0.16% 0.21% 0.28% 0.43% 0.65% 1.00% 1.40% 2.00% 3.00% 4.00% 6.00% 8.00% 11.00% 15.00% 21.00% 30.00% 1.47% 1.91% 2.71% 3.60% 4.41% 5.45% 7.43% 9.92% 13.29% 16.55% 20.71% 26.38% 31.01% 38.28% 43.81% 49.97% 55.53% 60.16% 61.89% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% 35.00% $ 37.5 $ 52.5 $ 82.5 $ 120.0 $ 157.5 $ 210.0 $ 322.5 $ 487.5 $ 750.0 $ 1,050.0 $ 1,500.0 $ 2,250.0 $ 3,000.0 $ 4,500.0 $ 6,000.0 $ 8,250.0 $ 11,250.0 $ 15,750.0 $ 22,500.0 $ 936 $ 1,218 $ 1,727 $ 2,295 $ 2,812 $ 3,475 $ 4,735 $ 6,325 $ 8,469 $ 10,553 $ 13,205 $ 16,817 $ 19,767 $ 24,405 $ 27,930 $ 31,858 $ 35,398 $ 38,351 $ 39,456 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313 $ 22,313</cell><cell>Assumptions D-SIB Small Bank ROE IRB (Lending Rate = 3%; LGD=10%) 42% 31% 21% 15% 11% 8% 4% 1% -1% -3% -5% -7% -8% -11% -14% -17% -21% -28% -39%</cell><cell>Loan Amount $10,000,000 ROE Standardised (Lending Funding Rate 1.00% 1.75% Rate = 3%) 2% 2% 2% 2% 1% 1% 1% 0% 0% -1% -3% -5% -8% -12% -17% -24% -33% -48% -69%</cell><cell>Expense $30,000 ROE Standardised ALT -A Typically not available as Alt-A 36% 36% 35% 35% 34% 33% 32% 29% 27% 22% 18% 11% 1% -13% -34%</cell><cell>(Lending Rate = 3%)</cell><cell>PD: probability of default, LGD: loss given default, ROE: return on equity, RR: risk rating, RWA: risk weighted assets, IRB: internal ratings based approach, D-SIB: domestic</cell><cell>systemically important bank</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 3 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions Vol. 13, 4 1-30 © Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 4 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 5</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 520/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions Vol. 13, 4 1-30 © Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 620/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 7</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 7 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions Vol. 13, 4 1-30 © Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 8 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 9</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 9 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 10 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 11</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1120/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1220/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 13</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1320/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 14 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 15</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1520/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1620/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 17</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 17 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1820/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 1920/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">20</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 21</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b2">21</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="22">Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions Vol. 13, 4 1-30 © Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b3">22</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 23</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">23</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b5">24</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 25</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd<ref type="bibr" target="#b6">25</ref> 20/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="26">Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions Vol. 13, 4 1-30 © Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 2620/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 27</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 2720/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 2820/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© Henry Stewart Publications 1752-8887 (2020) Vol. 13, 4 1-30 Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 29</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 2920/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">RMFI0178_OZDEMIR_GIESINGER.indd 3020/08/20 8:19 PM</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AUTHOR'S NOTE</head><p>The authors would like to thank the following organisations who graciously gave interviews for the purposes of this paper:</p><p>• </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">power to allow them to adjust prices when individual costs shift, such that their profit margins are maintained</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note type="raw_reference">power to allow them to adjust prices when individual costs shift, such that their profit margins are maintained.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of Commercial Bank Interest Margins and Profitability: Some International Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asli</forename><surname>Demirgüç-Kunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Huizinga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1596/1813-9450-1900</idno>
		<ptr type="open-access" target="http://www-wds.worldbank.org/external/default/WDSContentServer/WDSP/IB/1998/03/01/000009265_3980429111510/Rendered/PDF/multi_page.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The World Bank Economic Review</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1813-9450</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="408" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-11-30" />
			<publisher>The World Bank</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="raw_reference">Demirguc-Kunt, A. and Huizinga, H. (1999) &apos;Determinants of commercial bank interest margins and profitability: Some international evidence&apos;, The World Bank Economic Review, Vol 13, No. 2, pp. 379-408.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Funding Advantage and Market Discipline in the Canadian Banking Sector</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mehdi</forename><surname>Beyhaghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mordel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.1917498</idno>
		<ptr type="open-access" target="https://www.econstor.eu/bitstream/10419/95689/1/775227714.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SSRN Electronic Journal</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">SSRN Journal</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1556-5068</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="410" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="raw_reference">Beyhaghi, M., D&apos;Souza, C., Mordel, A. and Roberts, G. (2012) &apos;Funding advantage and market discipline in the Canadian banking sector&apos;, Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, Vol. 48, pp. 396-410.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of Interest Rates on Time Deposits and Savings Accounts: Macro Factors, Bank Risk, and Account Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bikker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gerritsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/irfi.12143</idno>
		<ptr type="open-access" target="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdfdirect/10.1111/irfi.12143" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Review of Finance</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">International Review of Finance</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1369-412X</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-08-29" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="raw_reference">Bikker, J. and Gerritsen, D. (2017) &apos;Determinants of interest rates on time deposits and savings accounts: Macro factors, bank risk, and account features&apos;, International Review of Finance, Vol. 18, pp. 169-216.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Australian government&apos;s competition policy review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mccluskey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>O'brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://parliament.nt.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/436119/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Harper Review</title>
		<editor>Appendix-Bii.-Competition-Policy-Revie~-Professor-Ian-Harper,-Peter-Anderson,-Su-McCluskey,-Michael-OBryan</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PDF (accessed 10th November</note>
	<note type="raw_reference">Harper, I., McCluskey, S., O&apos;brien, M. and Peter, A. (2015) &apos;Australian government&apos;s competition policy review&apos;, The Harper Review, available at: https://parliament.nt.gov.au/__data/ assets/pdf_file/0006/436119/Appendix-Bii.- Competition-Policy-Revie~-Professor-Ian- Harper,-Peter-Anderson,-Su-McCluskey,- Michael-OBryan,-March-2015.PDF (accessed 10th November, 2018).</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Domestic systemically important banks in Australia. Regulator performance framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Apr</forename><surname>Authority</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.apra.gov.au/sites/default/files/information-paper-domestic-systemically-important-banks-in-australia-december-2013.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>accessed 16th November</note>
	<note type="raw_reference">Authority APR (2013) &apos;Domestic systemically important banks in Australia. Regulator performance framework, available at: https:// www.apra.gov.au/sites/default/files/information- paper-domestic-systemically-important-banks- in-australia-december-2013.pdf (accessed 16th November, 2018).</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internal Ratings Based (IRB) approach: Clarifying PRA expectations</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Prudential Regulatory Authority</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S23" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="raw_reference">Prudential Regulatory Authority (2017) &apos;Internal Ratings Based (IRB) approach: Clarifying PRA expectations&apos;, Policy Statement PS23/17.</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
