<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/lopez/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Expanding the Copenhagen airport one-roof terminal</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Qvesel</surname></persName>
							<email>jonas.qvesel@cph.dk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">Lufthavnsboulevarden 6, P.O. Box 74, 2770 Kastrup, Denmark</note>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 74</postBox>
									<postCode>2770</postCode>
									<settlement>Lufthavnsboulevarden 6, Kastrup</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<note type="raw_affiliation">Lufthavnsboulevarden 6, P.O. Box 74, 2770 Kastrup, Denmark</note>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 74</postBox>
									<postCode>2770</postCode>
									<settlement>Lufthavnsboulevarden 6, Kastrup</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Expanding the Copenhagen airport one-roof terminal</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Received (in revised form): 18th February, 2020</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2020-11-01T13:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>terminal development</term>
					<term>terminal expansion</term>
					<term>vision statement</term>
					<term>cocreation</term>
					<term>stakeholder involvement</term>
					<term>flexibility. Master Planning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>is a Senior Master Planner with +12 years' experience in the airport industry and 20 years' experience in architecture and urban planning. With a degree in architecture from the Aarhus School of Architecture (2000), Jonas worked in the field of architectural design and urban planning prior to joining the Copenhagen Airports Master Planning team in 2007. Jonas has experience in master planning, terminal planning, demand analysis and airport infrastructure planning for most airport processesfrom runway capacity to terminal design guidelines. As Senior Master Planner, Jonas is currently master planning lead for terminal and baggage infrastructure development in CPH. In 2012-2014, Jonas was heading the initial master planning work on the airport´s new consolidated security check and landside terminal facility (in operation in 2018). In 2016-2017, Jonas was heading the initial planning work for the airport´s largest single construction project to date, the 'T3 airside expansion' project -and is currently part of T3A programme management with the responsibility of overall scope management and the architectural strategy for the project.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Some years into the future passengers moving through the airport will encounter a new part of the terminal: an expanded new departure lounge (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>) with the fami liar wooden f loor (trademark of CPH) and a waveshaped translucent ceiling -permeated by light like a crisp Scandinavian sky.</p><p>Vertical gardens pierce through the terminal space enabling daylight to enter the building and crea ting outdoor spaces for passengers, staff and crew to enjoy. To the south, facing the apron, a 270-by-10-metre glass façade presents a stunning vista to the Apron.</p><p>The description given of a future CPH terminal experience is in fact more than a vision; it ref lects the design concept for the future CPH one-roof terminal, which is currently being developed in the shape of the 'T3 airside expansion project' -the largest singular construction project in the history of Copenhagen Airport.</p><p>Following three years of initial planning and programming, the conceptual design for the project was initiated in March 2019 -with architects, engineers, contractors, airport specialists and project management engaging in a committed cocreation process. Simultaneously, enabling works on the construction site are progressing with the relocation of utilities, implementing a new terminal service road as well a new underground service tunnel -which are all needed in order to start construction of the new terminal building.</p><p>Located in the heart of the airport and with a total project footprint of 100,000 sqm, this is both a unique opportunity to shape the CPH terminal of the future but also an incredibly complex and challenging project to plan, design and execute.</p><p>Having been the project manager for the planning study for the T3 airside expansion project in 2016-2017 -and subsequently been part of the programme-management group -it has been my privilege to play a key role in the project since its inception. Early in the process, the project team and airport management realised that the magnitude, scope and complexity of the project required different solutions and an innovative mindset in order to succeed. We evaluated recent airport projects to better understand the strengths and weaknesses of our organi sation, decision-making process and methods of stakeholder involvement. We spoke to and visited other airports as well as other major Danish building clients, contractors and designers.</p><p>Part of the outcome of this process was a decision to develop the project by following three key principles -in design as well in execution:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Figure 1</formula><p>Rendering by Vilhelm Lauritzen Architects of future CPH departure lounge as envisioned in the T3 airside expansion project. Below on the ground floor, passengers will find the first stage of the new bag-reclaim hall providing increased capacity for inbound baggage retrieval and a completely new and improved arrival experience. © HENRY STEWART PUBLICATIONS 1750-1938 JOURNAL OF AIRPORT MANAGEMENT VOL. 14, NO. 4, 1-13 AUTUMN/FALL 2020 The purpose of this paper is to share our experience with this approach -focusing on practical and hands-on methodologies and learnings. In an industry where complexity and stakeholder involvement are well-known challenges, it is my hope that this paper will be of inspiration and use to others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT</head><p>Copenhagen airport is located less than ten kilometres from the centre of Copenhagen. The airport site footprint of 12 km 2 contains the runway system (two main runways and one cross-wind runway) in the centre, passenger terminal and apron area to the north, cargo to the east and ancillary support functions to the south and west. With the airport site constrained by the Øresund strait to the east (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>) and urban settlements on all other sides, efficient utilisation of available area is a constant priority for the airport in order to cater for traffic growth.</p><p>Overall, it is safe to say that CPH is a successful, attractive and efficient 1 airport. With 30.3 million passengers (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>) and more than 280,000 operations in 2019, the airport welcomed 85 airlines and 188 routes -43 of which were long-haul. In addition, 345,000 tonnes of cargo were shipped through CPH in 2019. For an airport located in a country of less than 6 million people, these are objectively impressive figures.</p><p>As illustrated on the graph, annual traffic in CPH has increased by 10 million passengers in the last 10 years. In order to deliver the needed capacity, service levels and operational efficiency required by customers, airlines, passengers and authorities, on-going development of the airport infrastructure has been a necessity -in conjunction with operational optimisation carried out in close collaboration with airlines and ground handlers.</p><p>Recently completed infrastructure and capacity projects include expansion of the centralised security check, landside terminal facilities for passenger f low and retail, a 5,500 sqm expansion of the airside terminal departure lounge and the opening of the first stage of CPH´s new international Pier E. Projects underway at this time include: a new baggage handling system (BHS) and hold baggage screening (HBS) facility, a new hotel and a multi-storey car-parking facility. And, of course, the project, which is the topic of this paper: 'T3 airside expansion project' including a new bag-reclaim facility, border control area, departure lounge with increased space for retail and passenger f lows and services and much more! THE 100-YEAR AIRPORT Of course, growth and development of the airport is nothing new. In fact, CPH is the oldest airport in the world still on the same site 2 and amazingly the first terminal of CPH still stands today. Built in the late thirties, the 'VL terminal' (named after its architect Vilhelm Lauritzen) is a modernist masterpiece: Spacious, elegant and highly functional and innovative for its time (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). Many years later -in the late nineties -the terminal was in the way of the airport's continued development, and it was decided to move the entire building to a new location 4 km south-west of the original site. Today, the terminal building, having been carefully restored to its original state, is used for VIP, education and administration purposes. The next major step in CPH terminal development came with Terminal 2 in 1960, which provided a spacious check-in hall and an elegant departure lounge (see <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). Plans were also made for an additional terminal further to the east -as well as an adjacent office and air control tower; these were, however, not built.</p><p>Instead, a completely different plan for the airport's future was being developed by the Danish Government: close the existing and build a completely new airport on the island of Saltholm in the middle of Øresund. The plan emerged in the mid-sixties and was driven in part by the introduction and increased volume of early (and very noisy) jet-powered aircraft, but also seen by the politicians as a possible element in the much-wanted rail/highway connection between Denmark and Sweden. In the end, however, the plan was not feasible, and a political decision was made, in 1978, to proceed with continued development of the existing airport instead.</p><p>Growth and expansion at CPH picked up in the late nineties with the opening of the new Terminal 3 (1998), including a new train station, check-in hall, arrivals facility and baggagesorting plant (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). Connectivity to the region was further improved with the Øresund train/ bridge complex to Sweden in 2000 and the opening of the airport metro station in 2007, which ensures a travel time to the centre of Copenhagen of no more than 15 minutes.</p><p>The benefits of excellent connectivity by public transportation (used by more than 60 per cent of passengers 3 ) is a key factor in the continuous development of the CPH master plan -including the decision to expand the existing 'Oneroof terminal' 4 rather than add new terminals further away.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Building the one-roof terminal of the future</head><p>The T3 airside expansion project is a key element in this strategy (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7</ref>). Adding 80,000 sqm of new terminal f loor space and refurbishing 20,000 sqm existing terminal areas, the project delivers a significant improvement to the airport's one-roof terminal capacity.</p><p>A key element in the project is delivery of a new bag-reclaim hall twice  On level +1, the airside departure lounge is expanded with an additional 24,000 sqm on two levels -providing improvements to passenger f low, services and dwelling -in connection with the further evolution of the very successful CPH airport retail and food and beverage environment.</p><p>The second-f loor level -occupied by public seating, restaurants as well as F&amp;B back-of-house, offices and staff facilities -is suspended from the terminal roof structure, minimising the need for columns and thus improving f lexibility of the terminal space and visibility and overview within the terminal space.</p><p>Four new vertical cores with installations, staircases and elevators connect the airside terminal space with the logistics basement and help to separate logistical f lows from passenger f lows (which has previously been a challenge within the existing terminal infrastructure).</p><p>To the east, the terminal space contains a new border-control facility for the Pier C international area (non-Schengen/Non-EU), doubling the space of the existing.</p><p>And on the top f loor -enjoying the benefits of daylight and an impressive 360-degree view to the airport, the Øresund strait and the city of Copenhagen -areas are created for a new airline lounge and additional office space for the users of the airport.</p><p>To realise the potential of this ambitious scheme and meet the challenges of execution in the very heart of an operational airport, three key principles have proven to be instrumental: The following section elaborates on each of the three principles -including the benefits and risks identified so far. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FOLLOW THE VISION</head><p>The purpose of a vision statement 5 is to serve as a clear and shared narrative of the outcome(s) to be achieved by a project, change or initiative.</p><p>In the case of T3 airside expansion, the function of the vision statement is to give direction for decisions on scope and design -and to provide the framework for communication and stakeholder involvement.</p><p>Early in the process, success criteria for the vision statement were defined as:</p><p>•</p><p>• Having a clear and concise image of the future state of the terminal.</p><p>•</p><p>• Reflecting the unique characteristics and identity of CPH.</p><p>•</p><p>• All stakeholders and users of the airport should be able to see themselves in the vision.</p><p>The vision statement was developed through the following main steps (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 8</ref>):</p><p>1. Value for stakeholders 2. Defining the CPH DNA 3. The future state of the airport terminal For the first step, the project team analysed and summarised the needs and preferences of five key airport stakeholder groups (see list given subsequently). The purpose was to identify the value and benefits that these stakeholders would be expecting the project to deliver. Examples of the value expected from each group are listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1 (not  extensive list)</ref> For the second step -'Defining the CPH DNA' -the task was to identify key elements, which sets CPH apart from other airport focusing on the significance of the airport´s geographical location in Scandinavia, Denmark and Copenhagen.</p><p>Today, the facilities in CPH ref lect some of the best qualities of Danish design and architecture; A welcoming atmosphere -accentuated by the human scale of the terminal space and the use of organic, warm material, such as wood. We want to continue this approach to airport architecture, while also taking in inspiration from contemporary developments in design of public space, infrastructure and commercial environments. As can be seen in multiple locations -in Copenhagen as well as cities across the world -there is a very special quality that can be generated in the public space where authentic experiences are created combining mobility and dwelling -and mixing existing infrastructure with innovative new design. These are all qualities which we believe should be part of the future CPH terminal experience.</p><p>For the third step -'the future state of the airport terminal' -key trends and future forecasts for aviation, airport and infrastructure development were analysed. In part it was done through desktop research, benchmark studies, site visits and conversations with other airports as well as through workshops and studies with consultants bringing together insights from aviation, airport development as well as non-airport Value for stakeholders "Outside-in perspective"</p><p>Defining the CPH DNA "Inside-out perspective"</p><p>The future state of the airport terminal "Outside-in perspective" One common theme, which is currently being addressed in many airports across the globe, is the need for airports to cater to the mental and physical wellbeing of not only passengers, but also staff and crew. In an increasingly technology-driven world -and in an industry where travelling from time zone to time zone puts pressure on the body and mind -the airport has an important role to play as a facilitator of wellbeing. For everyone passing through and spending time -whether for pleasure or business.</p><p>Through an iterative process, the result was eventually delivered. The vision statement for the T3 airside expansion project is illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 9</ref>.</p><p>In addition, eight strategic intents have been defined, setting more specific goals for the project to achieve (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A simple and flexible terminal concept</head><p>The mix of requirements and level of ambition for the project created a specific challenge in terms of short-term functionality versus long-term f lexibility. How to deliver a fully functional  Airlines New infrastructure supporting cost-efficiency of operations and short connection time. Commercial products supporting airline branding and special services (eg lounges).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ground Handlers</head><p>New infrastructure supporting cost-efficiency of operations. Work environment.</p><p>Retail Concessionaires Increased footfall. Improved airside terminal architecture and ambience. Improved facilities for logistics and staff. Work environment.</p><p>Airport authorities Airport capacity meets demand driven by expected growth in traffic. Support aviation connectivity within Denmark and to/from the outside world.</p><p>terminal facility (with all the technical and process-related complexities that this entails) within an operational airport environment, a strict time schedule and a geographically constrained construction site -while also creating a terminal building, which is highly adaptable to future needs and processes that are most likely not even identified yet? The key to approaching this challenge was asking ourselves the following two questions:</p><p>What are the required levels of f lexibility for each of the functional areas of the new terminal? For example: Level of f lexibility should be high in the departure lounge area (due to need for frequent changes to retail and passenger service facilities), but moderate in the layout of the bagreclaim hall and off-loading hall, where the priority is to deliver a fully functional and operational system as soon and as efficiently as possible.</p><p>What are the key structural and architectural elements, which serve as the core and basic structure for the terminal? For example: Overall spatial zoning on ground f loor. Vertical cores from basement level to all f loor levels providing circulation for staff, crew, waste, logistics as well as means of escape and technical installations.</p><p>Through analysis, discussion and design work during the early planning stage of the project, an overall layout concept for the future terminal was developed, which met the criteria of being clear, simple and easy to communicate.</p><p>Using the ground f loor plan as an example, the layout concept can be described as:</p><p>Overall strategy for the ground floor level was to prioritise functions that are essential to location on this level. As the terminal cannot easily be expanded further at a later stage without relocation of additional aircraft stands, it is essential that the functional disposition on this layout is dimensioned in an optimum way to handle future capacity needs (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 11)</ref>.</p><p>The ground f loor level is divided into three main zones: In addition, areas are allocated for support, service and technical functions between each main zone, including vertical circulation, escape routes, toilets etc. On the ground f loor level, adaptability is achieved in terms of options for phasing of new capacity. This is ensured by the modular linear layout of reclaim hall belts and off-loading positions, which enables implementation of new capacity in phases once the main terminal building structure is completed.</p><p>Flexibility in relation to changes of the layout is less relevant on this level due to the complex routing and multitude of interfaces needed for the technical infrastructure.</p><p>In comparison, the departure lounge level has a much higher level of f lexibility in the actual layout, as the changes to layout -for retail and/or passenger service needs -are expected to be much more frequent. On this level, the task for the design team is to ensure that the overall structural concept, evacuation strategy, installation routing etc are dimensioned and organised in a way so that subsequent changes to the terminal interior can be done with the least amount of impact.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and build by cocreation</head><p>Much like the concept of 'vision statement', 'cocreation' is a term frequently used in contemporary thinking and theory on organisations, change management etc. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The starting point, however, for CPH and the T3 airside project was not about theory, but about practical and communicative needs.</p><p>In general, cocreation is defined as a collaborative design process in which a wider range of stakeholders and future users are involved early -and have increased opportunity to inf luence the result compared to regular involvement processes in projects.</p><p>Conceptually, the cocreation setup was defined as a collaborative design process -with three main participants: The benefit of early involvement is that user requirements can be mapped early -and solutions drawn up and discussed. This is the phase where synergies appear, and risks can be identified and mitigated with minimal impact on the project´s overall cost, quality and time.</p><p>Cocreation also had a direct correlation to the contractual setup with the contractor and design team. The design and build contract have been split into two phases, where the first phase is for design and the second phase is for execution. By involving the contractor from the beginning of the conceptual design phase, valuable information can be exchanged between the airport, stakeholders and contractor/design team.</p><p>This means that -for example -the process for construction logistics can be planned in the optimum way -with consideration both for the airport (eg in terms of safety and security) as well as for the contractor (time, cost, staff etc).</p><p>Below the new terminal, a 10-metres basement in two levels will be housing the inbound BHS system as well as spaces for logistics, storage, wardrobes and technical installations. Excavation requires 400,000 tonnes of soil to be transported from the construction site to the southern part of the airport, where it will be integrated into the noise barriers towards the neighbouring community of Dragør.</p><p>This process has been a concern for airlines and handlers due to the risk of disturbances to apron operations from increased ground transportation traffic and foreign object debris (FOD). <ref type="bibr">7</ref> In this case, tests of transportation logistics were initiated early in the processincluding everything from procedures for covering, cleaning and marshalling of trucks -to implementation of new apron driveways providing optimum vehicle routes away from the construction site, with the least amount of impact on ground handling and aircraft taxying.</p><p>One key learning from this process is that it is not enough to plan and execute the critical processes in a reliable and proactive way; this needs to be combined with extensive involvement and continuous communication to airport users and stakeholders.</p><p>For the project as a whole, a mix of communication channels and fora are utilised -including everything from bilateral meetings, newsletters, site visit tours, broader information sessions and 'Q&amp;A'´s, where questions and concerns can be addressed in a constructive way.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Let me conclude by ref lecting on the learnings made so far by the project team and the airport.</p><p>In terms of adaptability, the learning has been that adaptability is not a binary state -ie adaptable or not -but a question of defining the level of adaptability for each of the different terminal areas. The benefit of having declared 'adaptability of the future terminal' as an overall goal from the start, was that it forced the project and design team to question decisions and priorities along the way.</p><p>As for cocreation, one can safely say that the term has been extremely successful in terms of creating a collaborative and constructive mindset for all involved. The challenge has been to ensure that the scope of inf luence for involved parties is always sufficiently clear. What is open for debate? What is not? When are the different parts of the project 'locked' for additional changes?</p><p>Finally: For any project, it is useful to occasionally step back and observe the wider perspective of what you are doing: Are we on the right track? Are we still</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>•••</head><label></label><figDesc>Follow the vision statement • • A simple and flexible terminal concept • Design and build by cocreation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2Aerial view of Copenhagen Airport with Øresund in the background</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 Graph showing the development of annual passenger volumes (million passengers per year) for 2009-2019</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 Figure 5 Figure 6</head><label>456</label><figDesc>Figure 4The VL terminal in its present location</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>••</head><label></label><figDesc>Follow the vision • • A simple and flexible terminal concept • • Design and build by cocreation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7The Terminal 3 airside expansion project located south of existing terminals and between Piers B and C</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8Main steps of developing the T3 airside expansion vision statement</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9The T3 airside vision statement</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>••Figure 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10The strategic intents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11Conceptual layout plan of future T3 airside ground floor</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Examples of needs and preferences of the five key airport stakeholder groups in relation to the T3 airside expansion project</figDesc><table><row><cell>Passengers</cell><cell>Short walking distances. Adequate space. Clear wayfinding.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Experience the joy of travelling.</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 313/05/20 1:18 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">© HENRY STEWART PUBLICATIONS 1750-1938 JOURNAL OF AIRPORT MANAGEMENT VOL. 14, NO. 4, 1-13 AUTUMN/FALL 2020</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 413/05/20 1:18 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 513/05/20 1:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 713/05/20 1:19 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 813/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 913/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 1013/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 1113/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 1213/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">JAM0254_QVESEL.indd 1313/05/20 1:20 PM</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>pursuing the goals that we spent so much time and effort to define -months (or years) prior? Or have we been sidetracked? If so, is it with good reason? Or is it because the details (which invariably increase in volume as the project progresses) have clouded our sight in relation to the ambitions and principles we decided at the beginning?</p><p>In this case, we benefit from being able to pick up the vision statement and consider: are we still creating an airport terminal where 'everything is within reach'?</p><p>In the end, we will need to wait for completion of the new terminal to pass verdict. Honestly, I cannot wait!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References and Notes</head><p>(1) Fourteen times within the last 16 years, CPH has been awarded the most efficient airport in Europe by the Air Transport Research Society (ATRS) -most recently in 2019, available at: http://www.atrsworld.org/docs/2019%20 ATRS%20Airport%20Efficiency%20 Award%20Winners.pdf (accessed 14th March, 2020).</p><p>(2 March, 2020). (7) FOD is the overall term used to describe any small item, particle etc that does not belong on an airport pavement surface and that can potentially cause harm to an aircraft that passes by.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
